♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Janine] Do you still
have feelings for Daddy?
Auntie Audrey is a big check for me!
See, you're blushing!
- [Janine] That's the grumpy man.
- Hey! You two!
She's the one who threw it, not me!
[Leon] You lying child, huh!
[Janine] I'll tell my mommy and daddy.
You're a bad person!
I didn't like what you did to my child.
Do you think I'm afraid of you?
[Leon] That's why there are unruly kids
because of people like you!
- [Leon] Come here!
- [Audrey gasps]
[Ibyang] That man is dangerous.
He has a gun!
- [gunfire]
- [Audrey screams] Atoy!
[Audrey] Atoy!
- [squeals]
- [gunfire]
- Come on, drive for me!
- S-Sorry.
I don't have the keys to my car.
- You're useless!
- [shrieks]
- I'll go with you instead.
- Where are the keys?
- [groans]
- [squeals]
[grunts and groans]
[Audrey] Thank you, Atoy.
[Willie] Don't take a job
that keeps you away too long.
Someone might hover around Cita.
- Eh, she's old now! No one will--
- Go home!
You don't even know, maybe Delfin
got to her behind your back.
You're an asshole!
- [bottle shatters]
- [groans]
That's a bad joke!
Run, you animal!
You'll pick up your guts on the street!
[growls]
I don't want my child to lose a father.
[Atoy] Is that really the only reason?
Or do you still want me?
I'm not the same Elaine
you met on the island.
Yes, I met other people.
But I looked for you in all of them.
[Atoy] That's why none of them lasted.
PREVIOUSLY
[suave music playing]
- [Ibyang] Auntie Audrey?
- [gasps]
- So many ants here.
- [Atoy] You're right.
[Audrey] Ouch.
[sneaky music playing]
- Ouch.
- [quirky sting]
Wait. What's that? What's that?
- Hey.
- [clears throat]
[quirky sting]
Ibyang, what's going on?
- I'm just a little hungry.
- [Atoy] Ahh.
Do you want-- A sandwich?
Do you want to eat?
Are you hungry?
Mm-hmm.
Did you kiss?
- Ah-- No!
- Huh?
What?
- What are you saying?
- [Audrey] It's nothing.
[titters]
- You really--
- You're silly.
Eh, because your lips look red.
[Ibyang] And Auntie Audrey's
lipstick faded.
Not really!
There's still some, see.
I just ate something, like…
Ah, what was it?
Annatto, yes.
Maybe-- Oh, I just ate annatto earlier.
[mutters]
Annatto.
Come on!
Let's eat. Come on.
[Atoy] Let's eat.
[music fades]
[suave theme music playing]
Paldo, thank you so much
for your donation to the church.
I can finally fix
the ceiling in the office.
Father, it's nothing.
Of course, I'm just making amends.
Why are you making amends?
You have no sin to the church.
[Noel] Willie, my friend,
let's talk about this!
- [growls]
- Let's talk about this!
[Willie] No friends here!
- [growling]
- Help me. Help--Help me!
Don't hide behind the priest!
He won't save you from hell!
[growling]
[tense music playing]
Willie, calm down!
Ah, God calls us to mercy,
not to violence!
Life is a sacred gift of God!
Ah, Willie, put down that knife.
Put it down.
Father, step aside,
and just pray for him!
[growling and groaning]
As long as I'm chairman here,
no one can stab anyone.
Do you understand?
- [Willie] Yes, Chairman.
- Answer!
- Yes, Chairman.
- [man] Go on.
You're an asshole, Willie!
[grunting]
Let me go.
You know it's forbidden
to cause trouble here in Tabang Lupa.
[music fades]
Well, Paldo!
Looks like you've changed.
Before, you were the spark
of trouble here,
but now, you're the one stopping it.
Oh my, praise God!
- [retches]
- [gasps, groans]
What-- What's wrong?
- What--
- Paldo!
[laughs]
[in English] The best!
[in English] You're the best!
Oh, you really are.
- [laughs]
- [retches]
Oh, God have mercy on you.
Yes, Noel.
Eh-- Stop drinking!
Yes, Sir Noel. That's enough.
Even I'll become
the cause of your trouble!
- Go home now.
- [Cita] Noel!
- [tense music playing]
- Oh no, you're in trouble.
Noel, what's wrong with you?!
You're so embarrassing!
You even vomited on Father! Let's go home.
- Did you make him drink?
- No.
[Cita] Sorry.
Come on! Let's go home--
- Go home, Sir Noel.
- [Cita] You said you'd look
- for work, but instead,
- Get some rest, get some rest.
you just drank.
You, you do nothing
- but drink!
- Eh, I'll go home!
- [Cita] You're so embarrassing!
- [Noel] Let's go home, let's go home!
[rousing music playing]
Wow, Mom, it stinks!
[Noel] Of course, I vomited.
[Cita] Get some water and a rag downstairs
and make coffee for your father.
Mom, we're leaving!
We have basketball with T-Bak!
- [Cita] Okay!
- Karla!
Karla! Karla!
It's late at night,
and you're still going out!
Let her be!
That's why her ego is so big.
What-- What…
did Willie say to you
that you suddenly hit him?
He's annoying!
You know, since you lost your job,
- you've been a burden!
- Hey!
Don't raise your voice at me, huh!
Don't forget!
I accepted you, huh!
I accepted you
with all your shenanigans, huh!
So, don't act all high and mighty with me!
- Hmm?!
- Get your hands off me!
- Don't act all high and mighty with me.
- [unsettling music playing]
Do you know?
Do you know what Willie told me?
Why I got mad at him?
My friend thinks Delfin stole you from me!
It's true, isn't it?!
How many times did you do it, huh?!
- How many times?!
- You're hurting me!
You're hurting me!
[growls]
Did you do it here in my own house?!
Did you defile our bed?!
No!
No! Ah--
- [heavy music playing]
- [groaning]
He's been dead a long time!
But until now, you still want him!
Noel, you're the one who mentioned him!
You're the one looking
for reasons to be angry at me!
That's over!
Whatever happened then, it's over!
What-- What-- What do you mean over?!
It happened!
It's-- It's over!
But the evidence is still there!
I see it every day!
Playing basketball!
And a headache!
[groans]
[music swells]
[music fades]
Whoa.
I was away for a short time.
That's almost gone!
Tatoy, don't you have anything to tell me?
Did something happen between you and…
Auntie Audrey?
- What happened? Psst. Hey, you.
- [quirky music playing]
You're still very young.
What are you saying?
What do you mean, "What happened?"
I'm not a child anymore.
And I get it.
What do you mean you get it?
It's bad to lie.
But am I lying?
[Ibyang] Hmm?
Like when you said you ate annatto,
that's why your lips were red?
Is there even an annatto tree
in this whole resort?
And Auntie Audrey said
she was bitten by ants.
But there were no ants there!
[sneaky music playing]
Did you get back together?
- [sighs]
- Yiee!
- [pleasant music playing]
- Your smile is different!
Oh, oh!
Tatoy is blushing, oh, oh.
It's like this.
We kissed.
Yiee!
- Yay!
- Oh, oh, psst.
But we didn't get back together. Not yet.
Anyway! Anyway, it's--
[in English] It's complicated.
[pensive music playing]
What are you doing here?
I need to talk to Audrey.
[smirks] What do you need from my sister?
You adults!
[music fades]
The one older than me.
Ahh.
[Ibyang] You, guys.
You even know "it's complicated".
Were you happy
when you were with Auntie Audrey?
Huh?
And do you feel giddy
when you're with her?
Eh…
[Ibyang] And…
you're not grumpy when she's around.
All check, right? Uh?
- [Ibyang] Huh?
- What do you think?
What's your opinion?
Hmm, yiee!
Tatoy, oh!
Don't let go of Auntie Audrey!
[light music playing]
It's like… a fairy tale come true.
- Really?
- You broke up, then…
- met again.
- Wow!
Yiee! That's true love!
I wish all had TL! Hmm.
Hey, Tatoy, oh.
- Tatoy, oh!
- [mutters]
You even know "TL-TL."
[Ibyang] Yiee, hmm.
- How do you know that?
- Hmm?
What are you watching?
Good news, by the way.
Tonet's brother
won't file charges anymore.
Looks like they know
they don't have a case.
[mysterious music playing]
[in English] Great.
But Atoy is really good, huh.
After everything we did
to cover up what happened to Tonet,
he still found evidence.
[clicks tongue]
I'm still not comfortable with that Atoy.
[sighs]
Audrey shouldn't have agreed
to co-parent with him.
We can't do anything, hon.
[in English] As long as they're
only doing co-parenting, we're…
we're safe for now.
[in English] You're not sure.
Didn't you see how Audrey
defended that Atoy?
What if they get back together?
What if they get married?
They can't get married.
[Red, in English] Exactly.
If they become husband and wife,
it's like letting a snake into the house.
[suspicious music playing]
[music fades]
What are you doing here?
Ah.
Just getting some air.
- [crickets chirping]
- [fire crackling]
[in English] Same.
Ibyang keeps pestering me.
She knows what happened.
[in English] About that.
Why did you kiss me?
[pensive music playing]
[in English] If the kiss was just a kiss
and nothing more, then…
Let's just forget it.
It wasn't nothing to me.
[light music playing]
What about you? Was it nothing to you?
[in English] I just want
to make sure that it was real.
[in English] I don't want
to play games, Atoy.
I want us to be whole for Janine.
Me too.
That's what I want too.
I want us to get back together.
But what about your family?
What about Red?
[scoffs] I don't care about him.
This is our family.
[mellow music playing]
[in English] Can…
[in English] Can we try to make this work?
I hope we last
for more than just this night.
I'm game for that.
We'll do this right.
For our family.
I don't see anyone else with me but you.
[sentimental music playing]
[phone ringing]
[in English] Ah, good morning, Dad!
Sorry, I just woke up, and…
We've been here at the resort
since yesterday.
How's your bonding with your daughter?
Are you okay there at the resort?
O-- We're fine here.
[chuckles]
Actually, can I talk to my granddaughter?
I didn't greet her yesterday.
Um…
- Who are you talking to so early?
- Shh!
Audrey?
Do you have someone with you there?
Oh, no, Dad!
Janine is in the bathroom.
Um, I'll just call you later, okay?
[in English] No, no, no, no.
Do you have a man
with you inside the room?
No, Dad.
[in English] Ah, I'll call you back later,
okay? Bye!
- [phone blips]
- [suspicious music playing]
You! My dad heard you! You're so noisy!
Oh?
Do you think your father will like me?
[in English] I think so.
[pensive music playing]
- Oh, my God, sir, ma'am!
- [squeals]
[staff, in English] Sorry to disturb you.
But are you checked in?
- Ah…
- No one is supposed to be here.
Sorry, miss. We'll just pay
for the overnight stay.
We have a honeymoon suite,
if you want to continue
your romance there.
Ah, is that so?
Okay, we'll just change clothes.
Atoy!
We came here for the kids,
not for a honeymoon!
[sneaky music playing]
Let's go, see them. Get dressed, quick!
Ah, I'll sleep first.
[music fades]
Ah, they're here.
- Ah, dear, we'll get food for you.
- [Janine] Okay.
Oh, what do you want?
What do you want to eat?
[Ibyang] All the dishes and eggs!
- All? Are you sure?
- Yes.
[muffled chattering in the distance]
Ibyang.
You can't sit here. Find another table.
Eh, the other tables are full.
If the other tables are full,
then eat in the room instead.
I just want our family at this table.
There.
But I want to be with Tatoy here.
And it's not your birthday anymore.
So, your birthday rules don't apply to me.
I just want to eat.
[rousing music playing]
[chair scraping, then utensils shattering]
- [gasps]
- Hey.
Are you okay? What happened?
Come here.
[groans]
Are you okay?
What? Where-- Where does it hurt?
Huh? Move your foot like this, like this.
Now the plates are broken.
You have to pay for that!
It's your fault.
You pulled the chair
just as I was about to sit.
No, I didn't.
So, it's my fault? It's all you!
So, what?
The chair moved on its own?
Don't blame me, Janine.
[in English] Don't me.
- [Ibyang, in English] Don't me!
- Don't shout at me!
You're not invited here.
You're not part of the family!
Psst, Janine.
[music swells]
Your attitude is still bad.
I gave you a chance on your birthday, huh!
You better leave.
- Hey.
- [in English] Janine, stop it!
Come with me! [sighs]
[Audrey] Come on! [sighs]
- [tense music playing]
- What happened?
Why are you fighting again?
Sir, I saw it.
The other girl pulled her seat,
that's why she fell.
Okay, thank you.
Yesterday you and Ibyang were okay.
Why are you fighting again?
She started it!
And why is it that Daddy
always sides with Ibyang?!
My dear, he's not siding with Ibyang!
He didn't say you were wrong!
Even so, Mommy.
I just want the two of you
to be with me on this vacation,
but I'm annoyed
because Daddy still takes care of Ibyang!
[pensive music playing]
And now he wants to adopt her!
Dear, that's why we want
you two to get along.
Mommy, no way.
Tell Daddy not to adopt Ibyang
because that means
we'll always be together!
I really don't like Ibyang, Mommy.
We'll never be friends.
We'll always fight!
[in English] Janine, please.
[sighs]
[in English] Mommy.
Why does he have to adopt Ibyang?
We don't need Ibyang in the family
because I'm already here!
Am I not enough as Daddy's child?
Doesn't he love me?!
[heavy music playing]
[sobs]
[Noel] Cita! Come on, eat now!
Stop acting up.
[Cita] I'll just finish this.
[Karla] Hey.
All of this food is mine!
If you want, cook your own or buy outside!
Noel, that's too much!
That food's all mine!
[pensive music playing]
I'll just eat at Brother Atoy's place.
What are you mumbling there?
Do you want me to choke?!
No!
I said I'll just eat
at Brother Atoy's place.
At least there, no one
will forbid me from eating.
Well then!
Eat there. Don't come back!
Enough!
If you don't want to eat,
then I'll eat it all.
Tatoy, aren't you going to scold Janine?
You heard it.
Someone saw her pull my chair.
I don't want bad vibes.
I don't want our vacation to be ruined.
[sighs]
Ibyang…
Don't-- Don't trigger Janine anymore.
I'll talk to her another day.
Okay? I don't want bad vibes.
- Um, so…
- Okay.
- [Ibyang] I'll try.
- [in English] Are we all good?
Janine, let's just forget
what happened, okay?
Let's just enjoy.
- Let's go fishing.
- Yes.
- Uh, Tatoy.
- [Atoy] Hmm?
I'll just go to the bathroom.
I'll follow later for fishing.
Ah, I'll pee too, Mommy.
- [Audrey] Ah, I'll go with you.
- No need.
Ibyang is here.
Promise, we won't fight.
- Promise, huh.
- [Janine] Yes.
Um, Ibyang, the bathroom
in the lobby is broken.
- But I know another bathroom.
- Okay.
Janine, is there really a bathroom here?
[sighs] There is.
Just follow me.
Fine.
Where is it?
[suspicious music playing]
What's that?
This really belonged to Sister Tonet.
I just took it…
so I could always be with her.
Ahh. Let me see, hmm.
Hey, Janine!
That's mine!
- Ibyang.
- Mmm.
Don't-- Hey!
[cackles]
They're taking so long.
Exactly.
Have you told Janine about us?
Not yet.
I wanted us to tell them together.
But Janine is still upset with you.
I don't know how we'll tell her.
[suspicious music playing]
Janine!
You said we wouldn't fight anymore,
but you're still making me angry!
Do whatever you want! [cackles]
Hey.
[tense music playing]
[Ibyang grunts]
Okay, that's it.
[sighs]
[cackles]
That's what happens.
- [thuds softly]
- [groans]
Ouchy.
[sighs]
- [foreboding music playing]
- [hissing]
[squeals]
[tense music playing]
You should thank me
because I accepted this child,
even though she's not mine!
Tell her the truth!
Delfin is your father!
Atoy is your brother!
‪UP NEXT
Because as long as Ibyang is here,
she'll always feel
that she's not enough for us.
Atoy, this isn't
a shallow insecurity that…
will just disappear when she grows up.
So, what do you want me to do now?
[Atoy] I'm sorry, Ibyang.
This is hard for me too, but…
to keep you from fighting with Janine…
You're not going to adopt me anymore?
♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias